yeah with the parable the parables Jesus
favorite method of teaching was through
object lessons mm-hmm and that's one of
the things that that you know I mean
this is kind of you know bringing in
when we need to learn how to see the
Bible as God so as God sees the Bible
right how to see the Bible as Jesus sees
the Bible a lot of times you hear this
term exegesis mm-hmm exegesis is they
attempt to get into the mind of the
author
what was the Arthur thinking as he was
writing right so when you're reading The
Book of Daniel or when you're reading
you know Isaiah you're trying to get
into the mind of Isaiah
what was the this what were their
surroundings at that time and when
Isaiah wrote this who was a letter to
and you know what was he what did he
mean by what he you're getting into the
mind of the author and and that's you
know praise God but guess what Isaiah is
not the ultimate author of the Book of
Isaiah right Daniel is not the ultimate
author of the Book of Daniel mm-hmm
right we're talking about the ultimate
author which is God himself which is
Jesus himself so I have to get into the
mind of Jesus if I want to understand
the full depth of the scriptures and
whoa what better way to have this mind
be in you which was in Christ Jesus yeah
that's why studying the Bible helps us
to receive the mind of Christ listen ask
Daniel if he understood half the things
he wrote
I'll try to get in Daniels mine I'm
gonna be right where Daniel was I
understood not I understand yeah right
yeah there was one greater than Daniel
who understood okay what did god intent
when he was telling Daniel to write
mm-hmm so that's where you know I really
see a need for us to begin to try to get
into the mind of God get into the mind
of Christ to understand the scriptures
yeah looking for Christ in the
scriptures that camera that Bible story
that text where is Christ in this story
mm-hm and that's so that would be a
juice down version thus far that is
amazing I mean really when you're
looking for Christ on every page I
remember you came you did a camp-meeting
a 3abn camp-meeting you preached it was
serious heartburn as you mentioned
earlier but you were talking about how
to find Jesus on every page and you gave
illustrations of that throughout the
Bible a juice down version juice down
right yeah yeah absolutely that that's
amazing and it really paints the picture
in a whole new light it makes you look
at the Bible and a whole new light man
well I like what you said about God
never waste
yeah anything any you know we know that
we know the way he moves he doesn't
waste
he doesn't just accomplish one thing
with one move he accomplishes many
things with one move right so it bears
to reason that he would have this whole
multi-dimensional aspect in the word all
right
you didn't just say multi-dimensional
did you I did you did didn't you
oh wait a minute he did and that's
that's nice that you said that it goes
what God is that is one of the aspects
of photo theology mm-hmm it's something
it's another principle that I have
called five dimensional Bible study the
mind of Christ so tell us some more
Pastor Myers about the five dimensional
aspects of study is that it so 5
dimensional Bible study and you know
what before I touch on that uh-huh we
were just talking over the break I
wanted to bring something up about the
importance of how to study the Bible
oh good because what you know what I
have seen in my experience is that you
know I'm a pastor right i pastored a
Campbell
you know seventh-day Adventist Church
and Campbell but what I have found in my
experience as a pastor is that you know
a lot of people in the church depend on
their pastor to study for them mmm
this is a good point you know it's it's
I believe that they you know the pastor
goes doesn't study put together his
sermon and then he preaches and the
people receive it oh man that was great
that was great where that the pastor's
feed the flock but sometimes a flock
depends strictly upon the pastor in
order to be fit I think one of the
things that we as pastors need to be
doing is not just feeding the flock but
actually teaching them how to feed
themselves yeah and you know I know that
I had never had someone come to me and
say listen this is how you study the
Bible like it's almost as if that was
reserved for the theology student it
wouldn't teach the theology students how
to study but for the rest of you you
don't really know what lead to learn how
to do that I mean you know kind of
figure stuff out on your own and
whatever but it's not that's not really
your burden but I think the more
educated our people are in terms of
learning how to get into the scriptures
for themselves yes you know it's almost
like we have the this tool that this
toolbox and you know the pastors this is
this is our tool of you know the tools
we use to study the Bible but we need to
be sharing those tools with our members
so that they are not equipped to get
into deep Bible study I think that one
of the things one of the I think the
underlying issue that we are facing in
our church
is how we approach the Scriptures
because how we approach the Scriptures
determines you know I mean look at all
the the controversies we have going on
in our church right now and I'm not
gonna name any of them right these are
all theological controversies right the
bottom line is these controversies are
coming up because there is a difference
in opinion in view of how to approach
the Scriptures and as long as that
exists no this is the right way to study
the Bible no this is the right way to
study the Bible your we're going to come
to different conclusions now I'm not
saying that there's a right way and a
wrong way to study the Bible but I don't
think there's any one right way to study
the Bible okay I think there's several
ways to approach the scriptures but the
way that you you know some people are
like well that way is you know this is
the only way and that I don't believe it
all because God the MA I mean I believe
that God has a thousand different ways
to reveal the same truth mm-hmm you know
and that's how I approach the Scriptures
so when someone approaches true gets the
truth in a way that I may not be you
know either familiar with or you know
I'm not sure how they arrived at that
particular truth but its truth I'm not
gonna knock the way that they got there
you know so I'm saying it got them there
to that truth and maybe that's how God
spoke to them but yeah you're so you
discover the truth about you know the
law of God okay well hate praise God
because you you came to that truth so we
need to I think there is a hermeneutical
crisis in our church interesting right
and you know this person's I know know
you know you're reading the Bible wrong
no no you're reading the Bible wrong and
you have like two scholars right that
have come to completely different
conclusions on the same text both
claiming we're scholars and yet you're
coming to two different conclusions so
there's a crisis in our church or
hermeneutical crisis and I think that is
something that we really need to begin
to pay attention to how do we approach
the scriptures do our members even know
how to approach the scriptures why why
and oh go ahead